<chapter>
	<title>eSciDoc Infrastructure Java Client Library</title>
	<section>
		<title>Communication with eSciDocCore Infrastructure</title>
		<para>
			The client library uses the eSciDocCore Infrastructure SOAP
			interface to invoke the methods of the resource handlers.
			The SOAP client classes are generated from eSciDocCore
			Infrastructure WSDL files.
		</para>
		<para>
			The host and port where eSciDocCore Infrastructure is
			deployed are configured via a user specific properties file.
			The default host is localhost, the default port is 8080. The
			default values are only taken in case no appropriate
			properties file is found.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Client Handlers</title>
		<para>
			Each deployed web service will have its own corresponding
			client, e.g. to access ItemHandlerService methods an
			ItemHandlerClient will be created. The ItemHandlerClient
			methods will have the same names but possibly an other
			signature, in fact all occurrences of the XML representation
			of an Item will be replaced by its Java representation. The
			method
		</para>
		<programlisting>
			String create(String itemXml) throws Exceptions
		</programlisting>
		<para>will be implemented as</para>
		<programlisting>
			ItemInterface create(ItemInterface item) throws Exceptions
		</programlisting>
		<para>
			and act as following: The method serializes the Item to its
			XML representation, fetches the SOAP client and calls the
			method create with the XML representation as parameter. If
			the method execution is successful and an Item XML is
			returned the new Item Java object will be instantiated with
			the Item XML and returned to the calling method. If an error
			occurs, i.e. the underlying SOAP client throws an exception,
			the exception will be thrown to the caller.
		</para>
		<para>
			and perform the following steps:
			<itemizedlist mark="opencircle" spacing="compact">
				<listitem>
					serialize the Item to its XML representation
				</listitem>
				<listitem>get the SOAP client of the Item</listitem>
				<listitem>
					call method create with the serialized XML
					representation as parameter
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					if method execution was successful:
					<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
						<listitem>
							a new Item Java object will be instantiated
							on the basis of the Item XML (created by
							ItemHandlerService)
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							the new Item Java object will be returned to
							the calling method
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>

				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					if an error occurs (i.e. the underlying SOAP client
					throws an exception):
					<itemizedlist spacing="compact">
						<listitem>
							the exception will be thrown to the calling
							method
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="API-REFERENCE" />
			contains a description for all available resource clients.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Data Binding</title>
		<para>
			For every resource (e.g. item) a Java representation besides
			the existing REST and SOAP representation is available.
			Every of these Java objects has an marshaller/unmarshaller
			based on the jibx framework (
			<emphasis>http://jibx.sourceforge.net/index.html</emphasis>
			) that is able to parse valid SOAP XML representation to
			create the corresponding Java representation, to update any
			values and to serialize to the SOAP XML representation. The
			details of marshalling/unmarshalling from XML to Java
			object and vice-versa are not really interesting for an
			application developed using the eSciDocCore infrastructure
			client library. Therefore the client handlers cover these
			details and only deal with Java objects in their interfaces.
		</para>
		<para>
			<xref linkend="API-REFERENCE" />
			contains a description for all available data binding
			classes.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>